<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Houston Real Estate Podcast with Daniela Antelo</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Keller Williams - your professional Houston Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>Daniela Antelo</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2020-04-21 09:28:33 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>Daniela Antelo</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>antelodani@gmail.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>Daniela Antelo</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>Daniela Antelo</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the Houston Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Keller Williams - your professional Houston Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Join Us for a Dinner With the Dumpling Dudez</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-join-us-for-a-dinner-with-the-dumpling-dudez-1.html</link>
        
          <category>Bienes raíces</category>
        
        <author>Daniela Antelo</author>
        <pubDate>2019-11-11 10:53:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Dani+Antelo/2019/Our+Referral+Raffle+is+Here!.mp4</guid>
        <description>

It’s November—and that means it’s also Gratitude Month. With so much of our business being referral-based, we want to give back to all of you for your continued support. We’re doing it by hosting a dinner party with the Dumpling Dudez. For the entire month of November, if you send us a referral of someone looking to buy, sell, or lease a property in Houston, you’ll be entered into a drawing. 10 lucky winners will be picked on November 30 to come to this dinner in January. If you have any other questions for us in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Dani+Antelo/2019/Our+Referral+Raffle+is+Here!.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Dani+Antelo/2019/Our+Referral+Raffle+is+Here!.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>To show you how thankful we are for your continued support, we’re raffling off an amazing dinner with the Dumpling Dudez for 10 of you. Here’s how to enter.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Daniela Antelo</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>To show you how thankful we are for your continued support, we’re raffling off an amazing dinner with the Dumpling Dudez for 10 of you. Here’s how to enter.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The REALtor Life</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-realtor-life.html</link>
        
        <author>Daniela Antelo</author>
        <pubDate>2019-09-04 10:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>

Do you know what it’s like to be a realtor? Contact me today if you are in the process of buying, selling or leasing a property! And by the way, I’m never too busy for any of your referrals.
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Do you know what it’s like to be a realtor?</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Daniela Antelo</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Do you know what it’s like to be a realtor?</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Ditch Your Ditch</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-ditch-your-ditch.html</link>
        
          <category>Bienes raíces</category>
        
        <author>Daniela Antelo</author>
        <pubDate>2019-08-01 15:21:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Dani+Antelo/2019/How+to+Ditch+Your+Ditch.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Today engineer Idalia Guerra joins me to talk about how you can convert the ditch in front of your house into usable parking space that will boost your property’s curb appeal. 

Feel free to follow along in the video above, or you can use the timestamps below to navigate the conversation at your leisure: 

0:44—Delving a little into Idalia’s career background  1:23—The initial steps you must take to convert your ditch2:03—What you can do with your ditch if you don’t want to turn it into more parking 2:36—Addressing flooding concerns3:22—Getting a topographical survey, having the civil engineer’s drawings reviewed by the city, and pulling your permit 4:37—Hiring your contractor 5:17—Who the ditch property belongs to and who’s responsible for maintaining it6:40—How the added parking boosts curb appeal and improves public safety 8:19—Idalia shows you an example of how to cover a ditch

If you have any questions about how to “ditch” your ditch or you have any other real estate needs I can take care of, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d love to help you.  

**Disclaimer: as of July 1, 2019, all plans must be approved by the city of Houston and planning commission. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Dani+Antelo/2019/How+to+Ditch+Your+Ditch.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Dani+Antelo/2019/How+to+Ditch+Your+Ditch.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Converting the ditch in front of your house into a parking space will boost your property’s curb appeal—here’s how you can do it.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Daniela Antelo</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Converting the ditch in front of your house into a parking space will boost your property’s curb appeal—here’s how you can do it.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>What Are the 5 Factors That Influence a Home’s Asking Price?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/what-are-the-5-factors-that-influence-a-homes-asking-price.html</link>
        
          <category>Bienes raíces</category>
        
        <author>Daniela Antelo</author>
        <pubDate>2019-07-30 12:51:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Dani+Antelo/2019/Five+Factors+that+Influence+a+Home's+Value.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Pricing a home is part science, part art, and understanding the reasoning behind this pricing will make you a smarter buyer and help you understand exactly what you’re getting for your money. 

Before sticking a “For Sale” sign in front of a home, here are the five factors Realtors look at when pricing it:

1. What’s happening in your local market. Real estate conditions can change quickly, so understanding what’s going on now is very important. For example, how fast are properties being snapped up? Is it a buyer’s or seller’s market? Low inventory means it’s a seller’s market and there’s more room to push prices up, while high inventory means it’s a buyer’s market. Our market, in particular, can change quickly, so you need to keep yourself updated. 

2. The specific location of the home. I’m not just talking about its ZIP code—I’m talking about whether there are good schools nearby, it sits in a cul-de-sac or backs up to a busy street, etc. It’s worth noting that in most areas, homes that have easier access to a highway fetch a higher sale price.  

3. A comparative market analysis. Oftentimes, sellers will already have a number in mind when I meet them for a listing presentation, and this number isn’t necessarily the most accurate. Homeowners tend to develop an emotional attachment to their homes over time and think it’s worth more than it is. A Realtor will be able to look at comparable properties on the MLS that have sold in the past six months to give the home a comparative market analysis. The MLS provides a lot of good information for this purpose, too. 

4. The home’s amenities (and overall appeal). Today’s buyers look at more than just a home’s square footage. Most of the time, they prefer brand-name appliances, larger bedrooms and closets, lots of light, central air conditioning, outdoor space, easy parking, and, in general, new construction over older homes. Layout and functionality are also huge pluses in terms of desirability, which means older homes that aren’t upgraded will be priced lower. 

5. Whether or not it’s a fixer-upper. You won’t get a lower price just because you’re thinking of buying a fixer-upper—location plays a big role in pricing these types of homes too. On the other hand, if you’re buying a newer turnkey property, expect to pay more for it because quality trumps quantity every time. 

“Real estate conditions can change quickly, so understanding what’s going on now is very important.”

If you have any more questions about how homes are priced or you’re a seller and you want to know what your home is worth, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I’d love to speak with you.  

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Dani+Antelo/2019/Five+Factors+that+Influence+a+Home's+Value.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Dani+Antelo/2019/Five+Factors+that+Influence+a+Home's+Value.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When it comes to pricing a home, there are five factors that Realtors weigh.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Daniela Antelo</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When it comes to pricing a home, there are five factors that Realtors weigh.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Crucial Parts of a Homebuyer’s Offer</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-crucial-parts-of-a-homebuyers-offer.html</link>
        
          <category>Bienes raíces</category>
        
        <author>Daniela Antelo</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-25 14:36:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Dani+Antelo/2019/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+Elements+of+an+offer.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Often when I’m out with buyers who have found a home they want to buy, they turn to me and ask, “What do we do now?”

The first thing I do when this happens is study the comps to make sure that our offer is backed up by actual numbers and that the price presented to us by the listing agent is, in fact, in line with the home’s actual market value.

Once we come up with a price, we’ll then proceed to make an offer. On page 167 of my book, “How to Buy a House in Houston, TX,” I include examples of the offer documents that we use. Written up by the Texas Real Estate Commission, these contracts are standardized, promulgated forms that we download and fill in as we solidify our offer. Remember that it is incredibly important to fill out these forms correctly.

Here’s an overview of what you’ll find on these documents:

At the top of the form, there’s a section where you’ll fill in the names of each party (the buyers and the sellers).

Following that, there’s a space for you to fill in how much you’re offering to the seller in terms of the sales price, as well as how much of a down payment you’re putting down. You might think that you’ll need to put down 20%, but sometimes you’ll find that you only need to put down 5% or 10%; as long as your lender is OK with it, that number can change at any moment.

Next, you’ll state how much you’ll put in for an earnest money deposit. For those unfamiliar, an earnest money deposit is basically a promise to the seller that you, as the buyer, are serious about making the purchase. The amount is normally 1% of the asking price. Once the contract is signed by both parties, the buyer must deliver this deposit to the title company, which can be selected by the buyer or the seller. For homes that aren’t new construction, the seller typically pays for the title policy.

The next important part of an offer to pay close attention to is the closing date, which is the date on which the sale will actually happen. Typically a contract can be closed between 30 and 45 days.

Beyond that, there are sections in which the following information can be filled in:


  Any special provisions you may want to address with respect to the house
  Any settlements and expenses. For example, are you asking for closing cost contributions?
  Any addendums that we plan to include in the contract


Finally, on page 8 of this form, you’ll find the “termination option” section. Many people have asked me what it means for a home to be ‘option pending’—this just means that the property has an accepted offer on the table. Once we have an accepted offer on the table and the contract has been both signed and executed, that’s when the option period begins.

“If you develop cold feet about the property or find a different property that you like more, the option period is the time to terminate the contract”

During the option period, you have 10 days to do your due diligence. This is the time to schedule an inspector to come view the property, talk to your neighbors about the neighborhood, or to talk to the City of Houston if you have particular questions about the home. You’ll also want to take this time to get quotes for home insurance to ensure that there are policies available that fit in your budget.

Further still, if you develop cold feet about the property or find a different property that you like more, the option period is the time to terminate the contract. If you terminate the contract during this period, you will get your earnest money deposit back, but you won’t get the $100 to $500 option fee back.

Hopefully this information has been helpful to you! If you have any questions about placing an offer on a property, feel free to contact me. I’d be happy to walk you through the contract. If you’d like even more detailed information about purchasing a home, I encourage you to look into my book, “How to Buy a House in Houston, TX.” 

 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Dani+Antelo/2019/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+Elements+of+an+offer.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Dani+Antelo/2019/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+Elements+of+an+offer.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>When it comes to presenting an offer on a home to the seller, there are a few key elements of the offer itself to consider. Find out what they are right here.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Daniela Antelo</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>When it comes to presenting an offer on a home to the seller, there are a few key elements of the offer itself to consider. Find out what they are right here.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Can You Improve Houston By Plogging?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-can-you-improve-houston-by-plogging.html</link>
        
          <category>Bienes raíces</category>
        
        <author>Daniela Antelo</author>
        <pubDate>2019-06-03 14:16:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Dani+Antelo/2019/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+Plogging+Challenge+Houston.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’ve been thinking a lot lately about why people decide to live in the neighborhoods that they do. The bottom line, I think, is that people make communities great. It’s all about who lives there, what they do, and the little things that contribute to great communities. Recently, I was talking to my friend Sara, and she told me about a new exercise she’s been doing called “plogging.” 

Essentially, it’s the practice of picking up trash while jogging or walking. It’s very easy, very simple, and all you need is a pair of gloves and a plastic bag. The plogging movement started in Sweden a few years ago, and we’re doing our part to bring it to Houston. 

“The cleaner our drains are, the less likely it is that our streets will flood in the future.”

For the next two weeks, I’d love for you all to accept the plogging challenge. Next time you go for a walk or a run, adopt a drain in your neighborhood and get to plogging. After you’re done, take a picture of yourself holding the trash bag. Then, tag me on Instagram @YourHoustonBroker and make sure to include the hashtag #ploggingchallengehouston. At the end of the two weeks, you’ll be entered into a drawing to win four movie tickets.

And on August 3rd, you can join me for a fun community event with refreshments, raffle prizes. fresh air and good vibes! The event starts at 10 A.M. at the Stevens Elementary park (1910 Lamonte Ln., Houston, TX 77018). 

This is just a fun thing I wanted to do to help clean up our community a bit and demonstrate how we can help keep our drains clean. We’ve lived through some traumatic flooding here, so the cleaner our drains are, the less likely it is that our streets are going to flood. 

If you have any other questions for me in the meantime, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Dani+Antelo/2019/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+Plogging+Challenge+Houston.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://vyralmarketing.s3.amazonaws.com/Dani+Antelo/2019/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+Plogging+Challenge+Houston.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Plogging is a new kind of exercise that will do good things for your body and soul. Here’s how it works.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Daniela Antelo</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Plogging is a new kind of exercise that will do good things for your body and soul. Here’s how it works.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Avoid Paying Capital Gains Tax When Selling</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-avoid-paying-capital-gains-tax-when-selling.html</link>
        
          <category>Bienes raíces</category>
        
          <category>Consejos para vendedores de casas</category>
        
        <author>Daniela Antelo</author>
        <pubDate>2019-05-15 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+How+to+Avoid+Paying+Capital+Gains+Tax+When+Selling+(1).mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’ve got some advice to share with you today about how you can avoid paying capital gains taxes on the sale of your home. Buying a home will be one of the largest investments of your life, so it’s good to know that there are some advantages to selling that property.

First off, what are capital gains? Items like cars, stocks, and bonds are all called capital assets. So is a home. When you sell an asset for more than you paid for it, the profit is called a capital gain. When you sell a car for more than what you paid, you have to report that to the IRS, who will tax you on that amount. However, homes are excluded from this capital gains tax, provided that you qualify.

Now, full disclaimer: I am not a CPA, I am just your Realtor. Double check all of this information with your CPA before doing anything.

“If you’re single, the exemption goes up to $250,000.”

What do you need to do to qualify for a capital gains tax exemption? First, you have to have owned the house for at least two years. You can also qualify for the exemption if you have lived in the home as your primary residence for at least two of the last five years. They don’t even have to be consecutive years. Finally, you can only use this exemption once every two years. If you’re planning on using this exemption in the future, I advise you to keep a record of how much you paid for the home and how much you’ve spent on improvements.

How much can you exempt? The amount depends on how you file. If you’re single, the exemption goes up to $250,000. For married couples, that amount doubles to $500,000. To find out how much your capital gains are, subtract your purchase price by your sale price. 

There’s been a recent change in the rules which allows exemptions on special circumstances, such as a spouse’s death. 

I wrote a book recently recalled“How to Buy a House in Houston, TX” that I’d be happy to get you a free copy of. If you want one or if you have any other real estate-related questions for me, don’t hesitate to reach out and give me a call or send me an email. I would love to hear from you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+How+to+Avoid+Paying+Capital+Gains+Tax+When+Selling+(1).mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+How+to+Avoid+Paying+Capital+Gains+Tax+When+Selling+(1).mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Most assets that you realize a profit on are taxed as capital gains. Home sales are an exception. Here’s why.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Daniela Antelo</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Most assets that you realize a profit on are taxed as capital gains. Home sales are an exception. Here’s why.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Latest Numbers From the Houston Market</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-latest-numbers-from-the-houston-market.html</link>
        
          <category>Actualización del mercado</category>
        
        <author>Daniela Antelo</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-25 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+The+Latest+Numbers+From+the+Houston+Market.mp4</guid>
        <description>

As we head deeper into spring here in Houston, buyers will love all the inventory that’s available. This is the time of year when sellers are putting their properties on the market, so you’ll have many choices to pick from.

On the other hand, homebuyers may hate all the competition this inventory is sure to generate, especially those in the price point between $250,000 and $350,000—properties in this range are being snatched up quicker than anything else. That means if you see something you like, you’d better put an offer on it now.

The weather doesn’t look as though it’s going to get any cooler, so remember when you’re out shopping for homes to wear comfortable shoes, drink plenty of water, and wear sunscreen. The Houston heat can really sneak up on you.

Whether you’re on the market this season or planning to enter it later in the year, you need to make sure that you’re ready to make a move when the time comes. It’s a complete myth that you need to put down 20% when purchasing a property; you can put as little as 5% down on a conventional loan or just 3.5% if you qualify for an FHA loan.

Earlier this year, I wrote a book called “How to Buy a House In Houston, Texas,” and I’d be happy to send you a copy if you’re interested in getting prepared for any market in any season. 

Starting at 1:38 in the video above, you’ll see a few charts that will tell you how each category has changed in terms of percentages from last year to this year. Single-family homes reached a 3.9-month supply in March 2019, which is up from a 3.3-month supply in March 2018—this marks the greatest supply of homes we’ve had since October 2018. For perspective, housing inventory across the U.S. is currently at a 3.5-month supply, according to the latest report from the National Association of Realtors.

“Earlier this year, I wrote a book called “How to Buy a House In Houston, Texas,” and I’d be happy to send you a copy if you’re interested in getting prepared for any market in any season.”

Home prices reached their highest levels ever this March. The median price increased 2.1% to $240,000. The average price rose 2% to $298,766.

At 64 days, the days on market, or the number of days it took the average home to sell, was completely unchanged from last year.

Townhomes and condos still remain a challenging segment of the Houston housing market. March brought us our seventh straight month of declining sales, dropping down 9.2% to 555 units sold, as compared to the 607 units sold just a year earlier. The average price was statistically flat at $211,241, while the median price rose 2.8% to $174,750. Inventory grew from a 3.6-month supply to a 4.4-month supply.

Whether you’re a buyer or a seller, if you’d like more information about what’s going on in our market, feel free to reach out to me at any time. I’d love to speak with you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+The+Latest+Numbers+From+the+Houston+Market.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+The+Latest+Numbers+From+the+Houston+Market.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Here’s your latest update on the Houston spring real estate market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Daniela Antelo</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Here’s your latest update on the Houston spring real estate market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Discovering Stevens Elementary</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/discovering-stevens-elementary.html</link>
        
          <category>Bienes raíces</category>
        
        <author>Daniela Antelo</author>
        <pubDate>2019-04-01 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+Discovering+Stevens+Elementary.mp4</guid>
        <description>

For my latest community spotlight video, I’m featuring Stevens Elementary School. I live close enough to this school that I can hear the principal’s voice over the loudspeaker from outside my house, so it only made sense for me to come take a visit. 

Joining me for this spotlight is Tim Weltin, a wraparound resource specialist who works with the school. In case you don’t know, a wraparound resource specialist is someone who helps with non-academic support within a school. Essentially, Tim assesses what the school needs and then matches those needs with community resources.

For your convenience, I’ve provided timestamps of our conversation so that you can skip ahead to the section(s) that interest you the most: 

0:33—A little background on Tim’s career and his involvement with the school 2:27—An overview of the programs available at the school and how people can get involved3:42—Getting to know the culture of Stevens Elementary 6:48—Why academic rating systems don’t tell the whole story of a school’s worth10:56—How the school’s SPARK park has benefited the community11:40—Where Tim sees Stevens Elementary headed in the next five years 13:35—A final message from Tim

If you’d like to know more about how you can give back to our Oak Forest community, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.

As a commitment to my local school, I will be donating a portion of all my sales in the 77018 zip code to the Stevens Elementary art department. 
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+Discovering+Stevens+Elementary.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+Discovering+Stevens+Elementary.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>In my ongoing quest to discover our Oak Forest community, I’m spotlighting Stevens Elementary School.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Daniela Antelo</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>In my ongoing quest to discover our Oak Forest community, I’m spotlighting Stevens Elementary School.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How Do Realtors Get Paid?</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-do-realtors-get-paid.html</link>
        
          <category>Consejos para el comprador de vivienda</category>
        
        <author>Daniela Antelo</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-24 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+What+Does+it+Cost+Buyers+to+Hire+a+Realtor_.mp4</guid>
        <description>

The goal of this blog is to provide answers to all your real estate questions. Recently, I was asked something very interesting: How do Realtors get paid?

Well, if you’ve been thinking of buying but have been worrying about the cost of hiring an agent, I’ve got amazing news: Working with a Realtor won’t cost you a cent. 

How can this be? Simply put, Realtors in Houston are paid a 6% commission rate (on average) at closing on a home’s final price, and this amount is paid by the seller. 

So if you previously assumed that hiring a Realtor to help you buy a home would only amount to more money out of your pocket, think again. Hiring an agent to help you find the perfect home will not only ensure a smoother experience overall, but it may also actually save you money.

“Realtors have the skills, experience, and resources necessary to point you in the right direction during your home search.”

The only thing you need to do is to sign a buyer representation agreement, which essentially states that you won’t be working with another Realtor for the next three to six months. Of course, many agents will be happy to let you out of this contract if you’re not satisfied with their service. 

Realtors have the skills, experience, and resources necessary to point you in the right direction during your home search. I recently wrote about this in my new book “How to Buy a House in Houston, Texas.” You can get a copy for yourself right here, or you can contact me directly so that we can speak about the real estate process in greater depth.

If you have any other questions or would like more information, feel free to give me a call or send me an email. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+What+Does+it+Cost+Buyers+to+Hire+a+Realtor_.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+What+Does+it+Cost+Buyers+to+Hire+a+Realtor_.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Someone recently asked me how Realtors get paid, and so I thought I’d cover this question for all of you today.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Daniela Antelo</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Someone recently asked me how Realtors get paid, and so I thought I’d cover this question for all of you today.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>2 Ways You Can Save Money as a Homeowner in 2019</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2-ways-you-can-save-money-as-a-homeowner-in-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Consejos para vendedores de casas</category>
        
        <author>Daniela Antelo</author>
        <pubDate>2019-03-07 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+2+Ways+You+Can+Save+Money+as+a+Homeowner+in+2019.mp4</guid>
        <description>

If you’re looking to save money as a homeowner in 2019, there are a couple of ways you can do so. 

First, if you currently live in your primary residence—not an investment property—you can file for homestead exemption. The deadline to file is coming up fast, though, and keep in mind that you must have lived in your current home as of January 1 of this year. 

To file for this exemption, you can either go online or download the application and submit it via mail. In the latter case, you’ll need a copy of your driver’s license with your primary residence listed. The filing process is completely free, so don’t fall for any spam mail that offers to file for you for a nominal fee.

“You might be surprised at how much of a reduction you get, and who doesn’t want that extra cash in their pocket?”

The second way you can save money is by protesting your property taxes. Property taxes tend to increase every year, but you can protest yours by bringing a copy of your property tax disclosure to the courthouse in person. Texas is a non-disclosure state, so remember that you’re not required to reveal how much you paid for your property. As with filing for homestead exemption, this process is free. 

If you’d like help protesting your property taxes, I would be happy to do a comparative market analysis of your local area to supplement your position. In any case, don’t be afraid to give it a shot. You might be surprised at how much of a reduction you get, and who doesn’t want that extra cash in their pocket?

If you have any more questions about this topic or you have any other real estate needs I can take care of, don’t hesitate to reach out to me. I’d be happy to help you.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+2+Ways+You+Can+Save+Money+as+a+Homeowner+in+2019.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+2+Ways+You+Can+Save+Money+as+a+Homeowner+in+2019.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>If you’re looking to save money as a homeowner in 2019, I want to tell you about a couple of ways you can do so.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Daniela Antelo</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>If you’re looking to save money as a homeowner in 2019, I want to tell you about a couple of ways you can do so.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>The Habits You Need for Being a Successful Home Seller</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-habits-you-need-for-being-a-successful-home-seller.html</link>
        
          <category>Consejos para vendedores de casas</category>
        
        <author>Daniela Antelo</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-27 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+The+Habits+You+Need+for+Being+a+Successful+Home+Seller.mp4</guid>
        <description>

We’re experiencing a bit of a buyer’s market, so if you want to sell your home, it really needs to stand out. When there are ten other listings in your area, how can you possibly expect to make a sale? Don’t worry, because today we’ll be going over the habits you can put in place that will help you sell your home successfully:

1. Tidy up. Keep your home clean each and every day. If you move something out of place, make sure to put it back where it came from.

2. Respond to offers as soon as possible. Timely responses have the most success when it comes to negotiating contracts and getting to the closing table.

3. Build buzz about your house. Your Realtor will be doing this for you, but you should be spreading the news to colleagues, peers, and social media. Let everyone know how amazing your house is—you never know who’s listening!

“If you want to sell your home, it really needs to stand out.”

4. Deep clean. Try to do this every week by hiring a cleaning service or doing it yourself. Keep it spotless and make sure dust doesn’t begin to accumulate.

5. Apply the Marie Kondo method. If you’re familiar with her book or Netflix show, you know exactly what I’m talking about. Begin purging your house of anything that doesn’t bring you joy and keep the rest neat, organized, and put away.

6. Maintain your exterior. The No. 1 thing buyers notice is your curb appeal, so make sure your landscaping and exterior are looking great each month.

Sit down with your agent. Do this each month and talk about trends, what’s sold, and what’s been happening in real estate. Find out what you can do to make your listing stand out.

Make repairs. I recommend bringing in an inspector each year in order to figure out what needs to be fixed. You want to make sure things are in good shape!

If you have any questions about making your home stand out or you need further information, feel free to reach out to me. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+The+Habits+You+Need+for+Being+a+Successful+Home+Seller.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+The+Habits+You+Need+for+Being+a+Successful+Home+Seller.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>You’ll easily be able to sell your home if you keep these tips in mind.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Daniela Antelo</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>You’ll easily be able to sell your home if you keep these tips in mind.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Know When You’re Ready to Buy a Home</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/how-to-know-when-youre-ready-to-buy-a-home.html</link>
        
          <category>Consejos para el comprador de vivienda</category>
        
        <author>Daniela Antelo</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-07 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+How+to+Know+When+Youre+Ready+to+Buy+a+Home.mp4</guid>
        <description>

People often tell me they can’t buy a home for a variety of reasons. They can’t afford it, it’s not the right time, and so on. My response is always this: How do you know?

If you haven’t done your homework, you really have no idea whether you can buy or not. You may be surprised to find you’re more ready than you think. In fact, I’ve written a book on how to find out.

My book, “How to Buy a House in Houston, TX,” will give you everything you need to know about getting ready to start the home search. The very first step in the process is setting up a meeting with a lender. They’ll look at your finances, credit, and more to determine what you can afford.

“There are always great opportunities in Houston real estate.”

There are always great opportunities in Houston real estate, especially now that we’re undergoing a shift toward a buyer’s market.

If you’re ready to begin your search, have any questions, or would like to learn more, give me a call at 713-494-8170 or email antelodani@gmail.com. I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+How+to+Know+When+Youre+Ready+to+Buy+a+Home.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+How+to+Know+When+Youre+Ready+to+Buy+a+Home.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Did you convince yourself that you can’t afford your home? Well, you may be surprised to find that might not be the case.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Daniela Antelo</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Did you convince yourself that you can’t afford your home? Well, you may be surprised to find that might not be the case.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Our Market Now and How Buyers & Sellers Have a Lot to Gain in 2019</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/our-market-now-and-how-buyers-sellers-have-a-lot-to-gain-in-2019.html</link>
        
          <category>Actualización del mercado</category>
        
          <category>Bienes raíces</category>
        
          <category>Consejos para vendedores de casas</category>
        
        <author>Daniela Antelo</author>
        <pubDate>2019-01-28 18:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+Our+Market+Now+and+How+Buyers+%26+Sellers+Have+a+Lot+to+Gain+in+2019.mp4</guid>
        <description>

Many have wondered, “How is our Houston market looking?” The truth is, it was a slow December—one of the slowest since I got my start in real estate.

That all changed when we entered 2019. My phone has been ringing off the hook!

“The bottom line is, in terms of real estate, Houston is a very healthy place to be.”

What I’m seeing from our market right now is that it’s in the hands of buyers. Inventory is high and interest rates remain fairly low. With all the talk of interest rates going up, though, buyers should heed this information and not delay in taking action while rates stay where they are.

Now that the holiday craze is behind us, sellers should begin to turn their attention and get serious about putting their homes on the market.

The bottom line is, in terms of real estate, Houston is a very healthy place to be.If you have any real estate-related questions for me or for help with any and all of your real estate needs, please reach out to me by phone at 713-494-8170 or by email at AnteloDani@KW.com. I’d love to be of assistance!
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+Our+Market+Now+and+How+Buyers+%26+Sellers+Have+a+Lot+to+Gain+in+2019.mp4" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/Dani+Antelo/Daniela+Antelo+Keller+Williams+_+Our+Market+Now+and+How+Buyers+%26+Sellers+Have+a+Lot+to+Gain+in+2019.mp4" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>Today I’ll dive into the current state of our market and how both buyers and sellers can gain the most from their move in 2019.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Daniela Antelo</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>Today I’ll dive into the current state of our market and how both buyers and sellers can gain the most from their move in 2019.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome To My Blog!</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-my-blog.html</link>
        
          <category>Actualización del mercado</category>
        
          <category>Bienes raíces</category>
        
          <category>Consejos para vendedores de casas</category>
        
        <author>Daniela Antelo</author>
        <pubDate>2018-05-09 19:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <guid></guid>
        <description>Our market remains busy, and it’s still an opportune time to command a high price selling your home.  

I know what’s happening in the Houston area, specifically pertaining to home values, that will directly affect you.

So, I’ll be posting two monthly video messages on this blog to keep you updated.

They will be valuable and useful in helping you stay on top of what’s happening in the community.

Check back because content will be coming soon!

I’m excited to keep you updated on what’s happening in the Houston area!
</description>
        <enclosure url="" length="" type=""/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="" type=""/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>My monthly messages will provide you with market updates, tips, and other educational information having to do with our market.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>Daniela Antelo</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>My monthly messages will provide you with market updates, tips, and other educational information having to do with our market.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in Houston, home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>Daniela Antelo</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">Daniela Antelo</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from Keller Williams - your professional Houston Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
